Guide to the Kiwanis Club of Walla Walla records 1922-1993
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
Kiwanis Club of Walla Walla records
1922-1993
Whitman College and Northwest Archives 345 Boyer Avenue Walla Walla, WA 99362 Archives@whitman.edu https://library.whitman.edu/archives/
Kiwanis Club (Walla Walla, Wash.)
WCMss.032
3.8 linear feet 9 boxes
Records documenting the activities of a local service organization, the Kiwanis Club of Walla Walla, Washington, from 1922 to 1993
Collection is open for research.
Bulk of the collection donated to the Whitman College and Northwest Archives by Jay Gerbino, president of Walla Walla Kiwanis, on September 30, 2005. The accession number is 2005-004. The Songs of Kiwanis and Vance Orchard's papers were donated prior to August 2004.
By series; mostly alphabetically within series.
Kiwanis began in 1915 with the establishment of the first Kiwanis club in Michigan, and the organization soon expanded to other locations. Dedicated to fellowship and community service, Kiwanis became an international organization in 1916 with the addition of a Canadian Kiwanis club. Membership was extended to women in 1987. As of 2006, Kiwanis has become a worldwide service organization encompassing more than 8,400 clubs in 96 nations.
The Kiwanis Club of Walla Walla was organized in 1922 and received its charter later that same year. Activities of the club have generally focused on youth and community service projects, such as involvement in youth baseball teams and scholarships, Special Olympics, and Walla Walla Frontier Days. The first large-scale effort of the club was involvement in the development of the Whitman Monument grounds during the 1920s.
Since 1925, an important project of the club has been maintaining and running Camp Kiwanis. The camp property was donated to the Kiwanis Club by the Reynolds family and is sponsored by the Camp Kiwanis Foundation through the Kiwanis Club of Walla Walla. The camp is primarily used as a youth camp, and also as a retreat, recreational location, and meeting place for other organizations.
This collection provides information about the Kiwanis Club of Walla Walla's organization, membership, and activities in the community. The club's social and service activities are best documented in the Meeting Minutes, Activities and Events, Camp Kiwanis, and Publications series, while the Financial Records and Organizational Information series provide information about the club's finances, internal organization, and membership. Manuscripts concerning the history of the club can be found in the Organizational Information and Vance Orchard Papers series.
City and Town Life; Washington (State)
- Meeting Minutes, 1922-1991; 1
  This series consists of records documenting the meetings of the Walla Walla Kiwanis Club. Meeting minutes pertain to the regular weekly meetings of the club membership; activities included musical programs, committee reports, and Camp Kiwanis projects. Board minutes document the board meetings of the club; typical business of the board included treasurers' reports, fundraising projects, planning for upcoming activities, and deliberation on new members. Meeting sheets record the date and location of meetings, as well as information about the program, guests, and expenses.
  - Meeting Minutes, 1922-1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1925-1927 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Sheets, 1928-1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board Minutes, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board Minutes, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board Minutes, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board Minutes, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Financial Records, 1954-1992; 2
  This series contains various financial records of the club, including budgets, receipts, banking records, and bills. Records are not continuous, since it appears that recordkeeping activity was carried out by a number of individuals at different times.
  - Accounts, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Budgets, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Budgets, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Check Register, 1985-1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Court Services, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Directory Invoices, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Donation Slips, circa 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Financial Statements, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Paid Bills, 1983-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Proposed Budget, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Report on Financial Guidelines, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Savings Account, 1954-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous financial records, 1926-1933 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Sheets, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Sheets, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Accounts, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Organizational Information, 1922-1993; 3
  These records document the membership, structure, and affiliations of the Walla Walla Kiwanis Club.
  - Administrative Records, 1986-1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Annual Reports, 1960-1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Attendance Lists, 1981-1992 (Box 3, Folder 6-10)
  - Attendance Record Book, circa 1934-1939 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Ballots and Election Tally Sheets, 1982-1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - By-Laws and Amendments, 1938-1993 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Club Histories, 1931-1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Club Officers, 1922-1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Election Annual Report, 1967-1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Executive Member / Committee Chairmen, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - History--Whitman Monument, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Kiwanis Club Directory, 1927-1963; 1969; 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
  - "Kiwanis in Brief" pamphlet, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Membership Cards, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Membership Certificate, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Membership / Charter Miscellaneous, 1922-1959 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Membership Decal, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Membership Development Award, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Membership Information forms, 1966-1989 (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
  - Membership Packet, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Membership Proposal Forms, 1980-1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Membership Records, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Membership Roll, 1922-1940 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Monthly Reports, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Organizational Chart, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Pacific Northwest District, 1989-1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Pacific Northwest District Directory, 1953-1991 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - President's Files, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Protocol, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Public Relations, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Standing Committees, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Activities and Events, 1962-1993; 4
  This series consists of records pertaining to the various activities and fundraising efforts of the club, as well as special events such as anniversary celebrations. Files typically include materials such as correspondence, receipts, and accounting information.
  - Bowling, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Charter Dinner, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Concession Trailer, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Corn on the Cob Project, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Cycle Races, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Easter Lily Project, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Eddie Feighner Project, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Edith House Project, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fair, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fair Booth, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Fair Court, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fruitcake Fundraiser, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Kiwanis Capers, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Ladies Night Banquet--Installation Programs, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Lt. Gov. Training Conference, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Fundraising Projects, 1991; undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Peanuts, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Projects, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Seahawks Program, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - SEW Fair Booth, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Sound of Music Project, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Special Olympics, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Spring Conference, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Whitman Mission, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - 60th Anniversary Celebration, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - 70th Anniversary, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Camp Kiwanis, 1966-1989; 5
  This series is comprised of information relating to the creation and maintenance of Camp Kiwanis, including legal documents, financial records, and correspondence.
  - Camp Kiwanis Foundation financial statements, 1987-1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Camp Kiwanis Lease, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Camp Rules / Fees / Stationery, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Elliott Estate, 1979-1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Endowment Fund, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Legal Papers, 1966-1977 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Notes, Plans, Correspondence, By Laws, Article of Inc., Directions for Care of Pool, 1973-1977 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Oregon Laws on Camps, 1974-1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlets, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Publications, 1975-1992; 6
  This series contains publications of the Walla Walla Kiwanis Club, beginning with a bi-monthly bulletin known as the "K' Builder" from 1975 to 1989, then as "K-Lines" from 1989 to 1990. In 1992 the club's monthly newsletter was called "Oikos" (A Greek word meaning "to build"). These one-to-two-page publications informed members of subjects such as club activities, elections, new members, and upcoming events.
  - Bulletin, 1975-1990 (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
  - Newsletter, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Sound Recordings, 1952-1953; 7
  - "The Birth of Kiwanis," A Chronicle Recorded by Donald A. Johnston, First President of the First Kiwanis Club, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Untitled, 1953 (Box 3)
- Artifacts, 1952-1982; 8; 2 linear feet 1 box, 1 oversize box
  - Autographed Little League baseball, undated (Box 9)
  - Ceramic Kiwanis logo (40th Anniversary), undated (Box 9)
  - Certificate: First Prize Achievement Award, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - City of Walla Walla proclamation: Kiwanis Day, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Kiwanis seal imprinter, undated (Box 9)
  - Two photo printing blocks, undated (Box 9)
- Miscellaneous, 1927-1992; 1980-1992; 9
  This series includes club correspondence, certificates, interclub activities, a songbook, and a small number of photographs.
  - Certificates, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Certificate of Appreciation, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Elks Lodge, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1985-1992 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
  - Induction Speech, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Insurance, 1964-1978 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Interclubs, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Kiwanis Mail, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Legion of Honor, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Letterhead, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, 1987; undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - "Songs of Kiwanis", 1927 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondance, 1925-1940 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Vance Orchard Papers, 1927-1992; 10
  These papers belonged to a longtime member and historian of the club. They contain writings and notes on the history of the club, as well as a few newspaper clippings. Researchers should note that the second folder contains three floppy discs: two 3.5 inch and one 5.25 inch format.
  - Stories about Walla Walla Kiwanis Club, 1927-1991 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Kiwanis Club and Camp Kiwanis, 1982-1992 (Box 7, Folder 15)